Nicholas Platt

nickplatt4@gmail.com | (909) 293-8750 | Baltimore, Maryland | nickplatt.dev TS//SCI with FS Poly

Summary

Experienced software engineer and technical writer with professional work in front-end development, creating user-focused documentation, and working directly with multiple development teams. Familiar with working within a Linux environment. Extremely eager for learning and mentorship. Currently working towards a master's degree in Software Engineering. References can be obtained if requested.

Experience

Programming Projects

2019 - Present

- Soccerfront.io Soccerfront is a soccer live score web application built using Nodejs, Expressjs,
 HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Soccerfront pulls data from the API-FOOTBALL API and displays
 the information in an easy-to-use live score table and league table (standings) view. Currently,
 over 20 leagues/cups are supported! This is an ongoing project and new features will be added
 sporadically. Hosted on a DigitalOcean droplet running Linux and NGINX. https://soccerfront.io
- Personal Documentation Website A fully searchable and robust documentation site built using Material for MKDocs and written in Markdown. Multiple additional JavaScript modules, such as an image light gallery and scroll-to-top button added. Created to help facilitate personal learning and retain all information from books and classes attended. Hosted on a DigitalOcean droplet running Linux and Apache - https://docs.nicklyss.com

Software Engineer

May 2021 - Present

Boeing Intelligence & Analytics (BI&A) - Annapolis Junction, MD

- Worked within an Agile environment developing web applications using the following technologies: HTML, CSS, Java, React, MongoDB, JavaScript, and Apache Maven.
- Improved UI/UX design through miscellaneous front-end development, ensuring that compliance needs were met for users with disabilities.
- Utilized Git to manage the version control of different repositories of data.
- Created Swagger documentation from the ground up for interactive API documentation for integrators.
- Answered user questions through JIRA and created help tickets to track fixes for future cases.
- Directly worked with customer requests to build new features in software.
- Tested new features before release to users to ensure operability and document any issues/bugs.

Boeing Intelligence & Analytics (BI&A) - Annapolis Junction, MD

 Created, edited, modified, and compiled over 2,000 pages of tool documentation (within Confluence) to give analysts a resource to refer to with questions on how a specific tool functions and the capabilities available within the tool.

- Worked with multiple style guides for each tool's documentation, maintaining a cohesive and consistent design.
- Assisted users in chat, email, over the phone, and through JIRA ticketing helpdesk to quickly solve issues and get them back into the tools necessary to accomplish the mission.
- Worked directly with developers to learn the latest features and functionalities of the tools to better assist customers.
- Assisted in the creation and updating of learning materials to help train users how to take advantage of available features in the tool, ranging from basic introductions to advanced workflows
- Tested new features before release to production, while reporting bugs and suggestions directly to developers.
- Worked efficiently in an agile environment, meeting deadlines and sprint goals.
- Assisted with proposal writings for multimillion-dollar contracts, focusing on grammar and style compliance.

ELINT Analyst (2631)

August 2013 - August 2018

United States Marine Corps (USMC) - Fort Meade, MD

- Delivered full electromagnetic spectrum reporting of target electromagnetic space to enable combatant commanders to develop an operational course of action as part of the E-Space Analysis Center program.
- Successfully briefed, deploying units and interested offices, the capabilities offered by the E-Space Analysis Center.
- Maintained the office's Confluence space with relevant notes and request procedures for users.
- Efficiently arranged and participated in the analysis, processing, and distribution of strategic and tactical intelligence.
- Created detailed analytic products including radio spectrum analysis and GSM network intelligence that enabled various tactical actions including target exploitation, SIGINT mission support, and force protection measures.
- Worked closely with customers, tailoring reports to meet their standards and requirements.
- Completed and collaborated on over 200 serialized reports, utilizing multiple secure databases and tools while maintaining 100% compliance.

Education

M.S. Software Engineering

2021 - 2023

University of Maryland Global Campus (UMGC)

B.S. Computer Networking & Cybersecurity

2016 - 2020

University of Maryland Global Campus (UMGC) - 3.8 GPA

Skills

Programming Languages HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Python, SQL, Markdown, Git

Documentations Tools Confluence, MkDocs, Sphinx, Hugo

Microsoft Office Suite Word, Excel, PowerPoint, OneNote, Publisher

Misc. Software Atlassian Confluence/Jira, GitHub Desktop